Finding Aid for Mary P. Sinclair papers, 1967-1999
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Audio-visual material
  The audio-visual materials series (1.8 lin. ft.) contains videotapes, sound recordings (cassette and reel-to-reel), photographs, slides, anti-nuke slogan buttons, and rally flyers.
  - Photographs, slides and other visual material (Box 36)
    - "Michiganians of the Year," 1985 color photographs (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 36)
    - "Nuclear Power in Michigan," color slide presentation (Box 36)
    - Sinclair, Mary, speaking engagement 1993, 2 photographs color (Box 36)
    - Wastesite (Matteson Township, Branch County, MI) 1980, 3 photographs color (Box 36)
    - Visual materials, buttons with environmental statements undated (Box 36)
    - Visual materials, flyers, bumper stickers undated (Box 36)
    - Traffic intersection analysis, Dow Chemical Company 1970, 3 reels color (Box 36)
  - Videotapes
    - Costner, Pat: Presentation Regarding Hazardous Waste Incinerators [at Dow Chemical?] 1992, VHS (under 120 min.) (Box 36)
    - "Day by Day," production of WUCM-TV, interview with Mary Sinclair October 2, 1976, U-matic (ca. 25 min.) (Box 36)
    - Michigan Low-Level Radioactive Waste Authority: "Safely Managing Low-Level Radioactive Waste in Michigan," May 16, 1989, VHS, 22 minutes (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous: "Covert Palisades Meeting;" "LLRW Advisory Committee, Delta Township, March 2, 1990" "Johngrud", at Eco. Conf.;" "Lansing Hearing, LLRW January 23, 1990", VHS (Box 36)
    - ABC News April 8, 1995, VHS (Box 37)
    - Don't Waste Michigan Meeting, Ann Arbor February 5, 1995, 2 tapes; VHS (Box 37)
    - Don't Waste Michigan, News and Total Press Conference, Lansing September 7, 1994, VHS (Box 37)
    - Don't Waste Michigan, Intro for Mary Sinclair April 2, 1995, VHS (Box 37)
    - Fermi 2 Greenpeace Rally-Monroe, Michigan. Harvey Wasserman-Cyrus, etc. June 22, 1994, 3 tapes; VHS (Box 37)
    - Holland Physicians for Social Responsibility Meeting with Martha Drake October 10, 1990, VHS (Box 37)
    - Kalamazoo-Palisades Watch, Marv Olson, Nuclear Information and Research Service, Mary Sinclair, Michigan Citizens Against Toxic Substances, Rep. John Dingell, Michigan Energy Reform Coalition July 16, 1992, VHS (Box 37)
    - Low Level Radioactive Waste Board of Governors Organization Meeting (Prairie Island, Harvey Wasserman, Marvin Resnikoff and Marv Olson) March 16, 1995, VHS (Box 37)
    - NRC Investigates Palisades July 20, 1993, VHS (Box 37)
    - NRC Shirley Jackson at Palisades May 26, 1995, VHS (Box 37)
    - Nuclear Waste Storage/Yucca Flats, TV Segment, week of January 10, 1994, VHS (Box 37)
    - Press Conference-Lansing, Dry Casks at Palisades, Don't Waste Michigan, Coalition for Great Lakes, Nuclear Information and Research Service, David Wunsch, Beal, Michael J. Keegan, Donald Hafner, Marv Olson June 1, 1992 Eco-Conf., VHS (Box 37)
    - WILX Lansing Program with Mary Sinclair regarding Consumers Power Midland Plant March 12, 1984, U-matic (Box 37)
  - Audio cassette tapes
    - All Things Considered, Midland undated (Box 37)
    - Carl Johnson Memorial Panel, Physicians for Social Responsibility Annual Meeting, Denver March 23, 1990 (Box 37)
    - "From Jesse Riley," March 27, 1987 (Box 37)
    - Interview undated (Box 37)
    - "Joint Committee on Nuclear Energy Michigan Legislature: J. Keppler and Gregory Minor Testimony," October 15, 1979 (Box 37)
    - "Nuclear Power in Michigan" Great Lakes Energy Alliance, 15 min. 15 sec (Box 37)
    - Nuclear Study Group Forum undated, 3 audiocassettes (Box 37)
    - Mary Sinclair Interview April 12, 1976, 2 audiocassettes (Box 37)
    - Mary Sinclair Nuclear Energy Crisis April 29, 1973 (Box 37)
  - Reel-to-reel tapes
    - Four public service announcements: Anti-nuke spots from Richard H. Sandler, Washington, DC (Box 37)
Related Material
The Michigan State Archives also has a collection of Mary Sinclair papers.